# Bedelbaev Zulkarbek | Ruby on Rails Developer

email: zulkar@bedelbaev.com

GitHub | Telegram | Blog

Bishkek, Kyrgyz Republic

## **Personal Statement**

I am especially interested in creating object oriented, database-backed, web applications. My favorite frameworks are Ruby on Rails. I also enjoy fiddling with Javascript to make front end experiences more enjoyable for the end user. I like Open Source.

Interested in Elixir, Go, React.

## Skills

Ruby, Ruby on Rails, RSpec, Capybara, API, RESTful, JavaScript, CoffeeScript, jQuery, JSON, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, PostgreSQL, Scrum, TDD, Puma, Sidekiq, Git, MVC, ElasticSearch, Capistrano, Linux, OSX, Linux

## **Experience**

Ruby on Rails developer @ Easy Software Ltd. (Remote)

April 2018 - June 2018

My responsibilities:

- development of functions for Easy Redmine / Easy Project based on customer requirements in Custom Repositories (Bosh, Panasonic, Schneider Electric, Lear, etc)
- development of functions for optimizing the company's internal processes CRM,
  Invoicing, Payments, Basic Project management logic
- development of functions for the requirements and priorities of the directors of sales,
  support and consulting departments based on feedback from customers
- · communication with development and management team.

#### September 2017 - February 2018

#### My responsibilities:

- create web applications with Ruby, Ruby on Rails
- create API for mobile applications
- create docs and database structure for future applications

#### Ruby on Rails developer @ Spalmalo LLC.

April 2015 - August 2017

### My responsibilities:

- create web applications
- create docs and database structure for future applications
- instructed junior developers
- managed code with unit tests using RSpec
- redesign and mobile version (Twitter Bootstrap, CoffeeScript, Javascript)
- create hundreds of features using Ruby on Rails, HTML5, SCSS and JavaScript.
- create complex search using ElasticSearch and Searchkick
- · communication with development and management team.
- worked with graphic designers to translate designs into web pages.
- installation, configuration, and maintenance of Web application and databases.

#### PHP developer @ PhpFoxExpert

January 2013 - January 2014

#### My responsibilities:

- create of modules and plug-ins for PhpFox CMS
- create of modules for internal project http://sfsdar.com
- create of modules for http://socialenginepro.com
- · create web applications with Symphony, Codelgniter
- support product
- create docs and database structure for future application
- communication with development and management team.

### **University**

May 2011 - January 2013

My responsibilities:

- support of computer infrastructure
- · setting tasks for the staff of the center
- create of a web site on a turn-key basis, site support

Symphony, Codelgniter developer @ Freelancer (Remote)

January 2010 - January 2011

My responsibilities:

- · create web applications with Symphony, Codelgniter
- create docs and database structure for future applications
- support product

## **Education**

## **Kyrgyz National University**

Bishkek, Kyrgyz Republic

Kyrgyz-American Faculty and Internet | Master's degree, Specialty: Network technologies

2004 - 2010